Robin Smith

Email: robin@rsmith.io
Phone: +44 7481 919 740
Website: https://rsmith.io

Full-stack Python and Javascript web developer with experience in enterprise applications. I have a passion for best practices and seek challenging projects. I blog about software development topics and personal projects in my spare time.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer - Kaptio Travel (June 2017 - December 2017)

Designed and implemented a secure data integration and synchronisation solution to allow a customer to sell their products through a third-party vendor. Wrote itinerary pricing logic in two backend pricing APIs using Python, Pyramid and PostgreSQL, deployed in Heroku.

Quickly got up to speed on a new business domain, contributing immediately. Identified code that needed better automated testing and significantly increased reliability of pricing logic.

Freelance Web Developer - Insight Software (July 2015 - June 2017)

Full-stack work on a large application for Network Rail, using AngularJS and Flask and deployed in AWS.

Designed the server-side code architecture, using a service-oriented design. This sped up development, reduced complexity, increased testability and allowed the project to scale.

Introduced team code reviews, encouraging readable code and automated testing, leading by example.

Front-end work: graphing with responsive controls for visualisation and editing; data import and export into different formats; data set-up wizards; report-building and generation interfaces.

Back-end work: cost/benefit algorithms; Latex report generation; CRUD operations for complex data models; database design and migrations; automation of set-up and deployment to staging and production; set-up of headless front-end testing.

DevOps Engineer, Cloudreach Ltd. – Edinburgh (June 2013 – March 2015)

Used Chef and Splunk to automate creation of custom customer stacks and implement custom monitoring. Developed a reliable system to archive support case emails from Salesforce into Amazon S3, to save costs.

Worked on front-line support to fix critical issues in customer stacks, engaging the customer with great communication, followed up with investigation and process improvements and reported back to the customer.

Relocated to Vancouver in Canada with one other colleague to start up a new Network Operations Centre for Cloudreach in North America, with the aim to grow a team built on best practices. We interviewed and mentored 8 new DevOps engineers, leading to them becoming AWS-certified engineers. The team was recognised by Cloudreach for its high standards and upholding core values with a great team culture.

Software Developer, Cloudreach Ltd. - Edinburgh (October 2011 - June 2013)

The first developer in the Edinburgh office, worked on web applications using Django and Play frameworks, Heroku, Salesforce and AWS platforms.

Recognised by Cloudreach for being Easy To Work With at the annual awards in Hamburg in 2013.

Became a core developer on the company's first commercial product: Alumina Connect – an application deployed in Salesforce to synchronise, email, calendar and contacts data between Google Apps and Salesforce. Took on responsibility for weekly progress calls with the customer.

Wrote and maintained a tool using Bash to automate deployment of code from Bitbucket to Salesforce. This was used by the team in development of Alumina Connect, and by other parts of the business on separate customer projects.

Software **Development Skills**

Languages: Javascript Python 2 & 3 Ruby

HTML, CSS, SASS

Java Typescript Swift Bash, ZSH

MySQL, PostgreSQL

Frameworks & Tools:

AngularJS, React, Ruby on Rails, Flask, Pyramid, Django, Jekyll, iOS, Cocos2D Git, Gulp, Vagrant, Github, Bitbucket

Bamboo, CircleCI JIRA, Trello

Platforms: Methodologies:

Heroku Test-Driven Development Salesforce Continuous Integration

Google Apps DevOps

Education

2005 - 2009MPhys Physics with Astrophysics, University of Sussex

Degree class 2:1

Other Skills & Qualities

Efficient time management and work ethic

I take a positive approach to life and aim to make the most of each day. Handling the workload of a physics degree alongside paid employment and recreational activities has taught me efficiency, organisation and working to a self-disciplined schedule.

Communication and people skills

I have a strong sense for effective and clear communications, developed through a diverse range of experiences: Talks at TechMeetup events; Officer Training Corps (OTC); tutoring at the University of Sussex; presentations; scientific reports and essays.